hi
i am rahul shah
and i am ready to reveal the only
training program you will ever need to
build your own
forex millionaire portfolio
join me at the lazy millionaire summit
on 24 january 5 pm click on the link in
the description to block your free spot
hello viewers
welcome to the first profits daily
myself richard vatia
in this video i'll be discussing
one asset class where you should keep a
watch for a longer term point of view
it's the commodity uh asset class
i'll share the two
widely trade tracked uh i would say the
uh
index which is very very much important
for a commodity uh investor or commodity
trader
the first is thomson reuters commodity
index so if you look at the chart over
here this is tom thompson reuters
commodity index and if i look at the
weightage uh
the index is formed with the weightage
of energy around 39 percent agree around
41 percent precious metals with around
seven percent and industrial metals
somewhere around 13 percent so if you
look at uh the chart over here uh
the previous which was between 1997 to
it took 69 months to break out in 2003
and since 2003 to 2008 we saw a huge
rally into the uh commodity space
again it was largely by crude oil which
went to the three digit mark
but since then
since 2008 it continued to flow onto the
negative side
it went on to the southwards journey and
the every time we have seen that lower
and lower structures being built uh i
would say since around july 2008
and since
[Music]
then for the first time in 2021
precisely at 69 months again
we witnessed the breakout the breakdown
which happened and the breakout which
happened now in 2021 we again it took
around 69 months
and if you look at 1997 or 2003 where
the breakout happened
we saw a huge chunk of rally uh the
momentum was very fast and furious
though i'm not expecting that the
momentum will be so fast and curious for
next three four five years
but yes the breakout is very very strong
uh and
looking at the momentum uh i would
definitely look at the commodity space
into my bucket
and once the money starts flowing over
there that could be an exciting watch
my second chat is uh essentially snp uh
goldman sachs commodity index which is
known as snp gsci
and if you look at this chart okay uh
just looking at the weightage first
energy consists of around 61.62 percent
uh led by wta sweet crude which is
somewhere around 25 percent followed by
brand crude which is somewhere around uh
uh industrial matters which is somewhere
around 11 percent followed by agree
which is around uh 16 percent and the
livestock which is around seven point
two five percent
uh precious metal is not there into this
uh
snp goldman sex commodity index
if you look at this structure over here
since 2008 when the fall started
okay it was forming lower and lower
structure like we saw in function
reuters commodity in that and in 2021
for the first time it broke the lower
and over structure over here
and this is very much exciting for me
because the two widely uh
attract commodity index functionality
and snp both are breaking out
uh a very very crucial uh lower and
lower low structure
and we might see
uh the rally coming into the commodity
space
the only concern for me over here is uh
the fund flow uh if you look at the fund
flow it's basically moving into the
equities uh there are no uh if you look
at the u.s commodity etfs we haven't
seen any etfs uh the fund flows going
into the atms of the commodity space
beat the oil with the uh bullies bait
the silver uh industrial metals so
i think i'll wait for a trigger over
there when the front flow starts into
these etf you should definitely look for
uh some of this space over here if you
are an equity uh trader and investor you
should definitely look for uh the agree
and uh these
energy space because if you look at
thomson reuters agrees somewhere around
41 percent if you look at the snp
goldman sachs index they agree somewhere
around uh 16 17 percent so i think uh
fund might flow into the agree space as
well and the agree companies which are
direct directly benefiting from the
rising commodity prices could be a
beneficial over there so you can focus
on those stocks as well into
uh the equity space but uh definitely
one should look at this asset class uh
from a next uh two to four years uh
horizon and if we
just track if the fun flow starts moving
into the commodity space we might see
this commodity uh triggering a a good
bullish rally into the coming weeks
so before i sign off uh in case you
think
these videos are happening do comment
about your views into the comments space
and do not forget to click onto the like
button signing off bridget
the way you pick stocks the way you
build your portfolio and the way you
make money in the markets will change
radically and immediately that's my
guarantee
click here to reserve your free spot for
the lazy millionaire summit
see you there